AKI GAO

(703) 901-0568 | xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowht.ml | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack JavaScript Engineer with a passion for technology and innovation, In particular the web and distributed software systems. I offer three years of professional experience in full stack web application development from conception to delivery of performant and maintainable solutions using functional programming paradigms and test driven development in an Agile environment. My expertise range from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to scalable and fault-tolerant event-driven microservice infrastructures. In particular, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node js ecosystems, as well as cloud native and distributed architectures using Docker and Kubernetes.

Work Experience

Solutions Integrator - User1st, Washington D.C.

January 2020 - Present

• Develops custom accessibility features for external clients using JavaScript and CSS.

Full Stack Blockchain Developer - Alluminate, Washington D.C.

November 2017 - February 2018

- Provided high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed and maintained the company's homepage as well as the landing page for several products, including CryptoPets, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets, and CoinScore, a Cryptocurrency market intelligence platform.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for CryptoPets in partnership with Arcade Distillery.

Technologist - Booz Allen Hamilton, Herndon VA

May 2017 - November 2017

- Developed proof of concept Blockchain applications based on Ethereum for various government organizations, including the U.S. Treasury and the FDA.
- Worked across the stack from UX/UI design to implementation of front end and back end logic in React and Node/Express respectively, as well as application deployment to various cloud providers including AWS and Azure in an Agile environment using Kanban.
- Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master when necessary to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
- Participation, expertise and leadership in projects led to conversion of one project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a contract bid.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Shell (Bash)

UX/UI and Front End Technologies: Sketch, HTML, CSS, Emotion, PostCSS, React,

Storybook, Redux, Apollo Client DevOps Tools and Technologies:

Helm, Skaffold, CircleCI

Development and Testing Tools: Git, Yarn, Lerna, Webpack, Babel, Jest, ESlint

Back End and Database Technologies: Nodejs, Express, Apollo Server, Knex, PostgresSQL,

Redis

Infrastructure Technologies:

Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

B.S. Computer Engineering & B.S. Electrical Engineering

August 2016